In this video I'm going to show you how you can generate all of these collage style motion graphic animations with all of the sound effects using gpt image 2.0 and cdance 2.0 and it's actually really easy and fun to do.
So firstly I'm just going to go into how you generate the images and then how you generate the videos and I've got some prompt templates for people to use.
So just looking in here I'm in Atlas at the moment where a lot of generations was happening and the model we're using is gpt image 2.0 which is really good for this kind of style.
And we started off with like really simple prompts like as you can see here like it's just bold athletic sneaker, marketing poster, energetic collage composition.
I find up like no matter what your prompt is as long as it's just something to do with the poster and collage style. It really works like collage poster and the key thing that makes this work with the animation is just having layers to the images.
So you've got text, you've got sort of different images, you can see these could easily all be cut out as different sort of design layers as if you're in like photoshop or illustrator and that just makes the animation a whole lot easier.
Some of these were just coming out just really nice just like honestly one shot and not really having to think too much about the prompt but just sort of coming up with just a base idea.
And so what I ended up doing was like reverse engineering kind of some of the prompts and creating this template prompt here.
So what you're going to do is I'll link this in description, you're just going to copy this and we go into chat gpt, we paste it.
And what this should ask you for is either describe your idea or concept or you can upload an image reference.
So let's say you've like got an image of an object that you want or piece of clothing or just something you want to post it beyond upload that or you can just describe your idea.
I'm just going to show you how simple this is. I'm just going to go iPhone 17 all I'm going to give it which is just bare bones minimum to just show you how capable this is right.
So now I've got this incredibly long detailed prompt.
We could then just generate this in here which I will try or we could just go into the aggregate like artless and generate it down here.
I'm going to actually do it in both just to just see if there's actually any differences here.
So we're going to use model. I'm going to go on media.
I find that's a good balance. Let's go for let's also paste that in here.
Okay, so the one in chat gpt has been generated.
As you can see, this looks pretty decent with the iPhone 17 in the middle.
Even like the text details here look like the text is so good.
Look how small this text is in it and it actually still looks pretty clear.
Paul and Miz on the video more is not so great, but like as a collage style poster, like I'm very, very happy with that based off of just putting in iPhone 17 and the prompt.
And this is the perfect image now to basically animate all of these.
And if we go in and look at the artless ones, these are going to 16 by 9.
Don't really like that one, but as you can see, done a fairly similar job in terms of style compared to the one in chat gpt completely different tool.
But say model you can see here quite like that one again.
So you can just experiment around with these you generate as many as you like images are obviously super cheap generate
You can obviously go back in and just say maybe I actually want more of this color or less of this more of that and just tell chat gpt
What you like and what you don't like about this to then just regenerate the prompt and you just go back and forth until you find something that you like.
So now what we're going to do is now return these into a video animation.
And this is actually pretty easy as well.
It's just taking the image and using a prompt, which I've also got a template for and you'll get mix results with this just like the images.
But eventually you just find one that comes out quite nice.
And so what I've been doing in terms of the process is you want to take this here.
And basically what this is doing is saying analyze the uploaded reference image and create a cinematic AI video prompt where the artwork is constructed from nothing into the final composition.
So basically what I'm essentially telling the model to do chat gpt is analyze this image that I've generated and just create the video prompt for me.
You could also use this generic one here, but I've generated which essentially is just describing to do similar thing in terms of animate all the layers.
It's just not being specific to the image.
You can try both. I've had good results with just a generic template and also had good results with specific prompt templates.
So as you can see here, it's now crafting this and it will be obviously referencing specific things in terms of how to animate them, which sometimes it adheres to it.
Sometimes it doesn't. My god, look at the size of this prompt.
Oh my god. So now we're just going to copy this.
I'm going to go into our list, go to video, see that I'm going to use fast just because it's cheaper.
You can use fast mini and 2.0. I found the results are like every generation looks different
but I wouldn't say 2.0 looks necessarily any better than fast. Like some generations I've had fast looks really good.
Some mini looks okay, some 2.0 looks okay.
And so I would always go with fast and also say it to 7.20.
Five seconds is I found pretty good. You can go shorter, you can go longer.
I'm going to upload the image reference in here and then I'm going to copy and paste in my prompt.
Okay, that's saying it's over the 5,000 world limit. No problem.
I'm just going to say reduce this to under 5,000 characters, not a problem. That should just condense it down.
I'll be honest, I've used this before and I've never had one that long but that's not a problem.
I don't think it's too far over. So we just copy that, paste that in, generate.
What I'll do is I'll generate a few of these on each of the different models just so you can see the difference in output.
Let's go 780, generate, and let's finally go cdance 2.0, which is going to burn all my credits.
Definitely don't 4k, oh my god, don't use 4k on cdance. It's like $10.15 for like $10.15.
7.20, very happy at 720. I have actually just uploaded the wrong image for all of those as well.
I have uploaded the 9x16 and I'm asking for 16x9.
Not a problem. Let's actually just change this to 9x16 for all of them and just see what happens here.
Because I actually don't know how that's going to turn out.
I've put the 9x16 image in and asked for 16x9 output, which is fine.
Let's just change that to 9x16 and then finally on the fast model.
This one is a set to auto. Those are the ones that weren't some reason didn't set to auto.
We've got 6 here. We've got 16x9 ones. Maybe this one actually isn't 9x16.
These are all mostly generated. Just waiting for this one here. That's fine.
This one is the cdance 2.0 fast.
Not too bad. I love that it includes the sound effects.
If you don't want the sound effects and you don't want the music, you can just prompt at the end like no music or no sfx.
I personally like having the sfx music. You could probably get rid of.
You just prompt it to say get rid of the music.
But that's pretty good. The only part I don't like is that bit there is a bit strange.
But overall, as you can see, fairly easy to do and get a quite a nice flowing animation.
Let's look at this next one. This is the 16x9 one.
This is the cdance 2.0 mini model. Perhaps this is because it's 16x9 or perhaps it's the mini model.
And it's just too difficult. See, that's that shit. That's not very good.
We'll have a look at the other mini model one as well and see whether it also does bad.
Of which case I would rule out using the mini model for this one.
I said I have used the mini model before and it's done an alright job.
But in my opinion, fast is the most optimal model for these in terms of credits and also doing a decent job.
This one here is the cdance 2.0 one. So this is obviously going to be the most expensive generation.
Nice. This one is good.
I like that sound effect at the end. I don't like this part here. That's unrealistic.
But there's so much happening here. It doesn't really matter too much in my opinion.
But I don't love that one. And then we're just waiting for this one to generate.
This is cdance mini. Okay, mini is just not working here.
That one is not working. We could conclude mini doesn't work for this.
This one is probably the fast one I would imagine.
Yeah, so this is fast in the correct dimensions.
Okay, this one's nice. This is probably the best one so far.
All the layers are animating nicely. This animation is changing obviously different each time.
And you could probably go back into the prompt and just describe this if you wanted to.
Like if you've got an idea, I don't mind that to be fair.
It doesn't have to be super realistic. It kind of just has to look cool.
The sound effects be good.
But yeah, as you can see, like easy peasy works pretty well. Happy with that.
I will say the only caveat to generating at 720p is you do lose some of the details of the text here.
You can fix this with 1080 or you basically potentially generate an image that doesn't really have tiny text.
And you're going to get that problem across any video model, not just like this specific example of collage animations.
Like if I have text that small on an image and it goes into a video model,
they will all struggle to do that unless you're generating like on a sedan's 4K model, which is expensive.
So I would use that if you really, really have to.
You know, maybe it's like something going on client work or it's like, you know, you need the top, top, top quality then use 4K.
But the only problem is is then you'll get a different generation. It might not be the one that you want.
Actually, fuck it. I'll generate one in 4K. If I've got enough credits, I'm running out of credits.
I don't know how many credits that can cost. 4K, 5, so I'll not too much.
sedan's 2.0, 4K. Let's generate the 4K one and see how that comes out.
It's probably going to take a while. It don't take sort of a couple of minutes. That's for sure. It takes a few minutes.
So these are both generated right now. This is the sedan's 2.0 720 quality.
Nice.
Not too bad, but you see the animation. That don't like that.
So kind of worked. But again, if we compare that to the fast version, no better than the fast version in my opinion.
And then finally, now we've got the 4K one. Don't recommend this. Don't know how many.
Because 6,000 credits, I don't know how much that costs. I know it's usually like $1 a second.
Nice. Animation is nice.
It's just the clarity. I'm just going to download this and just show you the clarity of the text.
This is the only reason why I would probably use this model is if I need the text clarity.
Because it does just look, if we look here, it's actually held the clarity of the text there.
Look how small that text is, designed in California, QC pass, inspected.
Look how that date there look like. You cannot get that on any other model.
Do I think the animation is much better than the others? Not at all.
Not at all, to be honest. All of the start of them are all very similar in terms of they do the job of putting that on.
And then they've all done the animation kind of different. But the 4K does look nice.
It does look nice, but super expensive to run.
But overall, I think this is really fun and easy to do.
If you have any questions or you discover anything new or have your own really good prompt that you'd like to share,
then drop them in the comments. But other than that, have a nice week and I'll see you in the next video.